BROOKE BILLMAIER

SOFTWARE QAQC | FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

BILLM1BE@CMICH.EDU

BROOKEBILLMAIER.COM • GITHUB.COM/BROOKEBILLMAIER

Full-stack developer focused on creativity, improving functionality and solving problems with innovative solutions. My background in marketing and leadership allow me to see the potential of development in processes, people and design. Driven by passion and innovation, I love bringing efficient programming and responsive design together to deliver an interactive human experience.

SKILLS:

Front-End:	Back-End:	Databases:	Frameworks:	Tools & Other:
HTML	Ruby	SQL	Bootstrap	Git and Github
CSS	Node.js	MongoDB	Ruby on Rails	JSON
JavaScript		Mongoose	AngularJS	Adobe Suite
jQuery			Express	Microsoft Suite
SASS				

EXPERIENCE:

Software QAQC & Documentation Specialist

Ann Arbor, MI

GeoNexus December 2018 – Present

• Led, defined, and ensured quality testing and release process for software suite; Created software test plans, test cases, and QA/QC procedures

Web Development Fellow

Remote

General Assembly

September 2018 - December 2018

• Expanded knowledge of front- and back-end languages while creating a collection of custom websites and applications using today's leading development tools and techniques.

Projects:

- Connect 4: A two player game built utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.
- FindMeFido: A full-stack application built using Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express and EJS. This app is hosted on Heroku and includes 7 restful routes as well as authorization.
- Hidden Haunts: A team built full-stack application hosted on Heroku while using a MEAN stack. This
 app adheres to an MVC file structure while including full CRUD as well as authorization.
- <u>ADS</u>: A team built full-stack app built using Ruby on Rails, React, PostgreSQL and SASS.
- SourceGem: A web development shop created using Ruby on Rails, React, PostgreSQL and React Bootstrap.

R+L Global Logistics

Los Angeles, CA

Account Executive Intern

June 2017 – September 2017

- Research leads, develop entrance strategies, and qualify prospective transportation spend to generate new business partners as well as individual and branch profitability
- Present multiple modes of transportation to customers to build a complete transportation and supply chain solution while upholding a high level of customer service

Central Michigan University, CONNECT: CMU Cellular Services

Mt. Pleasant, MI

Marketing Specialist

June 2016 – June 2017

- Update company website and create graphics/promotional materials after looking at market trends, forecasts and new product information
- Implement marketing and advertising campaigns by assembling and analyzing sales forecasts; prepare marketing and advertising strategies, reports, plans, and objectives

EDUCATION:

General Assembly

December 2018

Web Development Immersive

Central Michigan University

December 2017

Marketing and Logistics Management